





#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- ➤ PMP-PMI®
- > PSM I ®
- Lean Six Sigma Green Belt®
- TCS Certified Quality Auditor (Internal TCS)
- Contextual Master (Internal TCS)
- ➤ ITIL (Internal TCS)
- Certified Recruiter (Internal TCS)
- Trained on AGILE ACP

## **SKILLS**

- Estimation and planning
- Hold good experience in managing end to end

## ALBERT GRACE KUMAR

Contact No: +91 9841107617 E-mail : <u>albert\_gk@hotmail.com</u>

Location : Chennai

Linkedin: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/albert-grace-kumar-a8706518/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/albert-grace-kumar-a8706518/</a>

#### **PROFILE**

Accomplished Mid Senior-level project manager with 15+ years of varied experience in IT infrastructure and Server Operations, Transition Management, Resource Management, Stakeholder Engagement, Dashboards, Operations Management and Team Management.

Experience in effectively collaborating, facilitating, leading and coaching multiple scrum teams. Experienced with Scrum and Kanban framework, removing impediments and self-management, while keep team focused on delivering values to the client in rapidly evolving and dynamic environments

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

| Company                                 | Roles                                  | Year                  |
|---|--|-----------------------|
| Tata Consultancy Services<br>13.9Years  | Senior Manager/Project<br>Manager      | Oct 2021 to Till Date |
|   | Project Manager                        | Jan 2015 to Sep 2021  |
|   | Transition Project Lead                | Mar 2010 to Dec 2014  |
|   | Technical Process Trainer              | May 2008 to Feb 2010  |
| Sutherland Global Services<br>2.5 years | Senior Process Trainer Tech<br>Support | Dec 2005 to May 2008  |

### **ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES**

- Led the successful delivery of more than 20+ operational projects of Retail CPG and Media Market research company for more than 15+years
- ✓ Responsible for a team size of 350 human resources across multiple locations India and Mexico. Projects worth of \$30 Million
- Worked closely with the product management team to scope customer requested features and determine which features would provide the highest return on investment
- Created alignment with leadership team on scheduling, budgeting, resource management, and cadence and style of progress reports
- ✓ Coach and develop associates, supervisors, and managers for performance improvement and for their own career development
- Identifies continuous improvements that will improve unit costs and service provided to the client
- ✓ SLA & KRA Performance Management
- ✓ Lead the management Support within the Information Management production environment by
- ✓ WFM Management Service Level; Work Prioritization Strategies,
  - Productivity (Reducing Shrinkages & tracking AHT)
- Manage workflow and resources to consistently meet our service standards even under pressure situations

# Infrastructure and development Projects

- Proven experience in managing Global client accounts of varied sizes and Geographies.
- > Team Management
- Knowledge in PM Tools such as Budget Planner, MS Projects, Jira Kanban Boards
- Experience in Contract management - SOW and amendment drafting
- Hands on experience in ticketing tools such as Service Now
- Possess strong Leadership, effective communication, Negotiation, Stakeholder engagement, Risk Management, Organization, and planning skills.
- Additional Responsibilities
  - CSR Champion for the unit
  - L&D Champion for the unit

- Work with technology to formulate technological solutions for operations to improve efficiency and quality Implemented rigorous monitoring of new features to ensure they continued to meet KPIs after the projects were closed
- Manage the project from start to completion including the resolution of project risks and issues
- ✓ Provided leadership and management of the project team
- Ensured project and program objectives and performance metrics are achieved
- Ensured that project deliverable meet the required quality standards and are accepted by the customer
- ✓ Responsible for regular customer and internal project status
- Responsible for organizing and leading project team and project governance team meetings
- ✓ Participated in the preparation of proposals and agreements
- Continuously focuses on project and program delivery excellence and high level of customer satisfaction
- ✓ Contract management SOW and amendment drafting
- ✓ Team Management- Manage 4 delivery managers who reports under me, fulfill their needs, and ensure seamless project delivery
- ✓ Conducting quarterly town-halls

#### **EDUCATION**

- Bachelor of Commerce from Annamalai University 2011
- ✓ Diploma Mech/ITI from Ministry of Defence and National Council of Vocational training 2004
- √ Higher Secondary from Kendriya Vidyalaya Air Force CBSE 2001
- ✓ SSLC from Kendriya Vidyalaya Air Force CBSE 1999

#### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

| Date of Birth   | 10/06/1984             |
|-----------------|------------------------|
| Marital status  | Married                |
| Languages Known | Tamil, English & Hindi |
| Notice Period   | 30 days                |

Albert Grace Kumar, Chennai.